to open this time variables and we will fill it with these descriptions. For example, this
is a root password and it's types of course string, create sensitive and this is my SQL okay
and this default is set to WordPress, WordPress, so we change the database then the last time
I recall it, we called it my app, now it is called WordPress and for my SQL user we
instead of my SQL user we set it to WP user or WordPress user, right,
and here we need to of course set this as well.
okay so we define the password of my SQL user password to be like this
okay so we have initialized, we set the variables for database and user and
initialize my SQL password and my root password that's right it okay and validate that it is
a successful okay cool so now we should set the final part here
we will set to it makes outputs to go from the output we need to open output of TF
so the WordPress re-direction will occur when we type HTTP local host the output value and go to
the container of my SQL that dot name or my SQL container okay we need to open the this time
we'll open the outputs.tf and we set it to WordPress URL to this value and this is a container
to redirect the connection with it with the database and let's see our let's see everything now
and just to make sure that everything is okay we will now we are ready to
deploy the Terraform but we need first to let's initialize it for Terraform initialize to initialize it
okay but we are back now the code now the Terraform has been successfully initialized
so if we can go here okay we can directly apply the Terraform and later we can verify
the three stages of the Terraform because there is initial phase plan phase to show you what
exactly will happen when you click on Terraform plan and finally it's execution so the two things
that we didn't of course fill is the root password and the root password and the root password
and the user password okay for the user SQL and the root so the Terraform when I click on
Terraform apply it will just just ask me for these two value to fill so let's try it
okay for the user for example let me set a member and you need to remember the password that you
set for the database user and for the root okay and it will ask you that four that is four changes
to be added or for four changes to be added for the MySQL container and for the Apache and nothing
to destroy or change so we just confirm by yes and wait for the doctors to be created
okay success should be successfully created if I click now on Docker
that spsa sorry Docker s - a I can see now that we have two new doctors create
this is this is currently running to called WP Apache and WP MySQL and
the other two are exited of course and this is the two new containers or doctors created
automatically by the Terraform so our Terraform now is working so
before you can test for the local host access you need to do a very important task first
you need to check for the old file okay
this is old configuration file because it is changed so you need to open the WP if you recall
this file from the previous episode or tutorial you can see that the database name it is the
old one so we need to change it to according to the changes that you have done so for example here
you will set it to database is called WordPress so we need to set it to WordPress this is a default
name and the user WP user and of course passwords is changed actually I have typed is
a very very simple password you need of course to use a complex password in the real-life
environment I use my SQL simply underscore words okay and it is the same variable if you can
recall from the main.tf I used the same naming convention that use in the main file which is not
secure to do in real-life of course and this is changed to WP-my SQL so we need to do these changes
okay before you can test so this is the configuration file you need to make sure it is
okay and before you can test the local host you need to inspect the WordPress and Apache
to make sure WordPress and MySQL to make sure that there are both on the same network so if you
can issue this comment inspect WPMI SQL - grab 820 networks this comment will bring you WP
underscore network okay and you can see that WordPress - MySQL it is in the WP underscore network
and it got these address often and if I click on this or try to check with I don't know the
other name let's check WP - Apache so if I can check with WP - Apache I can see that it is having
this the another address and the same network so we are cool in term of connection to the network
and in term of connection with the and with this configuration of the W WordPress configuration file
so you are ready now to type local host and see the direction to the WordPress for installation
okay it guides me to the WordPress installation and I will click on continue let's name it
WordPress site here and let's make it for example
for we at 123 confirm week password and let's click on install to install it
okay we have updated the password and let's log in with admin street okay finally we can log
in with the admin to the WordPress okay so moving here to the next part we want to apply the
terraform changes in a controlled environment so here we want to first create the the terraform new
device because we want to separate execution of the terraform in a separate or isolated environment
so we type this and we'd switch to to it we create a new workspace and switch to it
okay and now we can use a current workspace which are working on to execute our
comments and everything okay we are on device so we are on a separate or isolated part of our
environments okay cool so any changes now we would not affect the production environments okay
if I want to to make the script for example here I can create the deploy I can modify
the deploy script okay and if you can recall it it is let me go here
it is on our directory of github this one sorry I forgot m
let me clear this is the script if I can go to scripts
we can use the deploy let's open the deploy
okay this is the deployment script that we have already created
in the previous tutorial so we can modify it okay so that we can select work this workspace
okay to just work from it okay and we do everything that we want to do like initialization so
anyone that turned this script will not need even to type terraform initialize it will initialize
to the plan okay and with set will output so we'll show you the output of the plan and
also it will show to you that in JSON format the terraform plan is generated and after that
it can not approve it or apply the change so you can simply paste it here